Finding Aid for AIDS Partnership Michigan Records, 1983-2005
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
AIDS Partnership Michigan Records, 1983-2005
AIDS Partnership Michigan
3 linear feet
0560 Bj 2
AIDS Partnership Michigan is a Detroit-based organization that provides education about HIV/AIDS and also provides services for those affected by HIV. The organization was formed in 1996 through a merger between Wellness Networks, Inc. (founded 1983) and AIDS Care Connection (founded 1989). The record group is comprised mainly of board meeting minutes of Wellness Networks, Inc., but also included are annual reports, financial reports and educational pamphlets of AIDS Partnership Michigan and Wellness Networks, Inc.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated by AIDS Partnership Michigan (donor no. 9590 ) in April 2005.
The record group is open to research. However, researchers must sign an access agreement preserving the confidentiality of names recorded in the files.
AIDS Partnership Michigan is a Detroit-based organization focused on providing education about HIV and AIDS and services for those who are infected, or affected, by HIV/AIDS. They manage a hotline, both by phone and on the Internet, provide transportation and hot meals to patients, and run three test sites for HIV. They also provide counseling and referrals to community services for HIV/AIDS patients and distribute brochures and condoms. The majority of their funding is from federal grants, as well as through fund-raisers and donations. They have approximately 30 staff and over a hundred volunteers, and are governed by a board of directors.
AIDS Partnership Michigan was founded on April 1, 1996. It is the result of a merger between Wellness Networks, Inc. and AIDS Care Connection. Wellness Networks, Inc. was established in 1983 to deal with the emerging AIDS problem in the Detroit/Metro area. Their purpose was to provide education and services to help prevent the spread of AIDS and refer patients to social services. AIDS Care Connection was founded in 1989 to coordinate services for individuals affected by HIV.
For additional information, see the website of AIDS Partnership Michigan http://www.aidspartnership.org
The record group is divided into two series: Wellness Networks, Inc. and AIDS Partnership Michigan.
Subjects:
AIDS Partnership Michigan.; AIDS Care Connection.; AIDS (Disease)--Michigan.; AIDS (Disease)--Patients--Services for.; HIV-positive persons--Services for.; Wellness Networks (Organization)
Contributors:
Wellness Networks (Organization)
- Wellness Networks, Inc.
  Wellness Networks, Inc. (2.75 linear feet, 1983-1996) documents one of the two organizations that merged in 1996 to become AIDS Partnership Michigan. The majority of the papers are meeting minutes from the Board of Directors and Executive Committee, as well as some subcommittees. In addition to minutes, the meeting materials include correspondence, financial reports, articles, and statistics on the hotline callers. The meetings are arranged chronologically, subdivided by each meeting. After 1987, there are fewer papers for each meeting. The series also includes a few financial reports and pamphlets produced by the Wellness Network to educate the public about AIDS.
  - Board and Committee Meeting Minutes
    - 1983-May 1986, 16 folders (Box 1)
    - June1986-1988, 15 folders (Box 2)
    - 1989-March1996, 12 folders (Box 3)
  - Educational Pamphlets, 1991 and 1994 (Box 3)
  - Financial Reports, 1991-1995 (Box 3)
- AIDS Partnership Michigan
  AIDS Partnership Michigan (0.25 linear feet, 1996-2005) series includes meeting minutes, financial reports, pamphlets for advertising, fundraising, and education, annual reports, and strategic plans of the organization.
  - Annual Reports, 1997-2003 (Box 3)
  - Board and Committee Meeting Minutes, April 1996-June1997 (Box 3)
  - Educational Advertisements and Pamphlets (Box 3)
  - Financial Reports, 1996-2004, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Fundraising Gala Programs, 2000-2004 (Box 3)
  - Strategic Plans, 1999-2005 (Box 3)
Related materials
The newsletters of the Wellness Networks, Inc, from 1986 to 1994, and AIDS Partnership Michigan, from 1996 to 2005, are available at the Bentley Historical Library and have been cataloged separately.